{
    "uid": "7265ec1c-9773-4c7c-9ed4-2ea26e19f346",
    "title": "Wireshark Challenge 1",
    "instructions": "<p>The SOC at BulbaTech Innovations received an alert of abnormal traffic patterns and a high number of repeated queries originating from one of their external-facing endpoints (<code>172.16.1.16</code>).</p><p>Using your newfound Wireshark skills, perform network traffic analysis on the <code>wireshark_challenge.pcap</code> packet capture to produce findings for the report questions below.</p><h3>Challenge File:</h3><p><ul><li><code>02_Network_Security/02_Wireshark/Challenges/wireshark_challenge.pcap</code><ul></li></p>",
  
  
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "How many total packets are in the <code>wireshark_challenge.pcap</code> packet capture?",
            "type": "text_input",
            "hint": "Look for a section that displays properties about the capture file.",
            "placeholder": "Enter your answer here",
            "correct_answers": ["39106", "39106 packets"]  
        },
        {
            "question": "What was the first domain name queried and resolved in the capture?",
            "type": "text_input",
            "hint": "Try using a display filter for the specified protocol.",
            "placeholder": "Enter your answer here",
            "correct_answers": ["webmasterdev[.]com", "webmasterdev.com"]  
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the associated IP address of the domain name?",
            "type": "text_input",
            "hint": "The query response may contain the answer.",
            "placeholder": "Enter your answer here",
            "correct_answers": ["184.168.98.68"]  
        },
        {
            "question": "How many <b>HTTP</b> packets are contained in the capture file?",
            "type": "text_input",
            "placeholder": "Enter your answer here",
            "correct_answers": ["8"]  
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the <b>relative</b> path the victim accessed on the web server to request a file for download?",
            "type": "text_input",
            "placeholder": "/******/*******",
            "correct_answers": ["9GQ5A8/6ctf5JL", "/9GQ5A8/6ctf5JL"]  
        },
        {
            "question": "Based on the response header, what file type or format does the web server claim the downloaded file to be?",
            "type": "text_input",
            "hint": "Follow the <b>HTTP</b> stream, and look for the <b>Content-Type</b> response header.",
            "placeholder": "Enter your answer here",
            "correct_answers": ["image/gif", "gif", ".gif"]  
        },
        {
            "question": "However, what is the actual file signature or magic bytes contained in the file?",
            "type": "text_input",
            "hint": "Magic bytes, also referred to as magic numbers or <a href=\"https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_file_signatures\" target=\"_blank\">file signatures</a>, are sequences of bytes located at the very beginning of a file. They serve as a unique identifier for the file's format or type.",
            "placeholder": "Enter your answer here",
            "correct_answers": ["MZ"]  
        },
        {
            "question": "What command-line utility or program was used by the victim to download the file?",
            "type": "text_input",
            "hint": "Check the request headers.",
            "placeholder": "Enter your answer here",
            "correct_answers": ["Windows PowerShell", "powershell", "power shell", "windows power shell", "WindowsPowerShell", "Windows Power Shell 5.1", "windows-power-shell"]  
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the <b>sha256</b> hash of the downloaded file?",
            "type": "text_input",
            "hint": "You may need to export an HTTP object contained within the packet capture.",
            "placeholder": "Enter your answer here",
            "correct_answers": ["9b8ffdc8ba2b2caa485cca56a82b2dcbd251f65fb30bc88f0ac3da6704e4d3c6"]  
        },
        {
            "question": "Submit the uncovered hash to VirusTotal. Based on the popular threat label and tags, what type of malware did the endpoint get infected with?",
            "type": "text_input",
            "placeholder": "Enter your answer here",
            "correct_answers": ["trojan.midie/pikabot", "pikabot", "midie", "zenpak"]  
        },
        {
            "question": "What <b>protocol</b> makes up the majority of <b>UDP</b> packets?",
            "type": "text_input",
            "placeholder": "Enter your answer here",
            "correct_answers": ["dns", "domain name system"]  
        },
        {
            "question": "Look at the domain names that were queried within the capture. In <b>defanged</b> format, what is the base domain name that is continually queried?",
            "type": "text_input",
            "hint": "It might be helpful to open up a DNS packet in the <b>Packet Details Pane</b> first. From there, look for the field that contains the queried domain name and add it as a column.",
            "placeholder": "Enter your answer here",
            "correct_answers": ["steasteel[.]net", "dns[.]steasteel[.]net"]  
        },
        {
            "question": "Read up on <b>MITRE ATT&CK ID</b> <code>T1071.004</code>. What is the attack technique weâ€™re likely seeing in the PCAP file often known as?",
            "type": "text_input",
            "placeholder": "Enter your answer here",
            "correct_answers": ["DNS tunneling", "tunneling"]  
        }
    ]
  }